Well, well.
哈哈
A secret compartment.
这里竟然有暗格
Looks like my hunch was right.
看来我的直觉是对的
Who could be calling?
会是谁打来的呢
Perhaps it's the assassin who shot at me?
是狙击我的那个暗杀者吗
Your hunch?
直觉…吗
Now I know for sure.
你这家伙
You came here without any evidence just to trick me into giving you answers.
仅凭直觉就来套我的话吗
And if that's true?
是又如何呢
Acting like you don't care isn't going to trick me.
就算你故作镇定 也没办法吓唬我哦
But
不过
you can be of some use to me.
就让我也利用一下值得利用的人吧
Answer it.
你接吧
This isn't a bomb, right?
这不会是炸弹吧
Hit the red button to pick up.
你按红色按钮后就能接听了
Here goes nothing!
行 我豁出去了
Are you busy?
你在忙吗
That voice…
这声音…
No, it's no problem.
不 无妨
Give him the information.
让他也听听你的情报吧
Well, well.
哎呀哎呀
And one who already has a considerable tie to my shop.
您跟本店可真是有缘啊
Thank you for your patronage.
承蒙您的厚爱
Lord Solitaire.
雪天鸦大人
The Grocer!
杂货殿
So,
那么
how are things going?
进展如何
All the items you requested have come in.
您预定的商品已经准备好了
The complete internal phone records of the Police Department.
警视厅内所有的通话记录
There are two pieces of information that will interest you.
其中有两个情报是您感兴趣的
The first is in the present progressive form.
其中一个正在发生
Inspector Tsubaki Iwanome
岩野目椿警部补
is talking with someone believed to be former inspector Hosorogi.
好像正在与细吕木原监察官在通电话
Hosorogi!
细吕木
I didn't expect to hear that name here.
没想到我会在这里听到这名字
I see. So he's alive.
是吗 他还活着吗
I'll deliver the call log to you later.
我之后会再把通话记录传给您
Another piece of information is
另一个情报是
a number of incoming calls from a middleman in Shibuya to Inspector Habaki.
涩谷的中介屋 曾多次联系过幅木警视正
Just as I thought.
这倒是在我的意料之中
Good work.
辛苦你了
Thanks for your patronage.
多谢惠顾
So you have a direct line to The Grocer.
能直接与杂货殿取得联系的通讯器…
Can you sell it to me?
你可以把这个卖给我吗
No.
不可以
Still, I'd heard you were a broad-minded man, but this takes the cake.
虽然我早就听说过 你是个黑白通吃的人
The superintendent general personally instructed a criminal to wiretap someone.
但我实在是没想到警视总监 竟然会指示犯罪分子去窃听通话
Isn't it obvious?
这还用说
Why else do you think I'd grant so much liberty to a criminal,
你觉得为什么我会给他安排单人间
even if it's just a single individual?
让一名犯罪分子享有如此的自由呢
Alright.
好了
I've told you the name of the person behind the scenes.
我已经告诉你那个幕后黑手的名字了
The location of Inspector Habaki is also under surveillance.
幅木警视正的位置 也在我们警视厅的监控之下
It's up to you how that information is used.
该如何使用这个情报 就取决于你自己了
I see.
原来如此
So you can keep your own hands clean by putting me to work?
也就是说 你是为了不弄脏自己的手 所以才让我出马的吧
You're after the mastermind
你想知道的
who tried to have you killed and whatever lies beyond, right?
不就是那个想狙杀你的幕后黑手 和他的位置吗
One more thing.
还有一个
Of course, I will pay.
当然 我会支付报酬的
What else do you want?
你还想要什么
I want Inspector Tsubaki Iwanome's cell phone number.
给我岩野目椿警部补的手机号码
Solitaire?
雪天鸦
Takumi?
匠
Oh! Finally got through!
终于接通了
We will talk about the details later.
我之后再跟你细说情况
Keep an eye on your surroundings.
你先小心周围
We wish to return as soon as possible too,
虽然我们也想赶快回去…
but we'll be a little late.
但我们可能会多花点时间
What?
什么
How I miss
难以忘怀的
my hometown.
故乡
It's extremely sloppy to say the name of your contact over the phone.
居然把对方的名字给说了出来 你实在是太粗心了
Inspector Habaki.
幅木警视正
What are you talking about?
你在说些什么
You just called
你刚刚
the person over the phone, "Higuro," didn't you?
提到了冰黑对吧
Why would you be talking to the middleman in Shibuya?
你为什么要跟涩谷的中介屋通电话
Well…
这…
And
还有
what was that about "Sabaramond"?
塞巴拉隆多是什么
I really felt like I owed you one, you know.
我以前是真的很感激你
Wait, Sabaramond is…
等等 塞巴拉隆多是…
Sabara…
塞巴拉…
Mond…
隆多…
Said it.
说了
Said it, indeed.
确实说了
What's with these guys?
这些家伙是怎么回事
Said it.
说了…
Said it, indeed.
确实说了
Saiiiiiiid…
说说说说说说说说…
Is everything well with my old friends?
朋友们 是否还 平安无恙
Sabaramond… Said it.
塞巴拉隆多…说了…
No mistake about it…it…
毫无疑问 疑问…
Product.
产物
(Episode 17: The Matriarch)
(第17集 The Matriarch-家长-)
Product…duct…
产物…
Sabaramond'ssssss…
塞…巴拉隆多的…
Productttt…
产…物…
Leader.
系长
Whoa, whoa.
喂喂
Is this for real?
有没有搞错
Leader, these people are really lucky.
系长 这些人运气真好呢
First Lemmings, then Solitaire, and now Fire-breathing Bug.
旅鼠军团 雪天鸦还有赴火之虫
This is what they call
我们这种情况
getting the joker.
简直就是抽到了鬼牌
THIS WORLD IS A BUGGY PROGRAM Darn it.
(这个世界满是虚伪) 可恶
When the wind blows.
狂风起
When the rain falls.
大雨下
My heart remains the same.
我心不改
My hometown,
故乡啊
I can't forget you.
我不能把你忘怀
Right?
对吧
Please drop away.
请散去吧
Please stand back.
请退去吧
All you weak little bugs.
各位孱弱的虫子们
My silly little brother is not a product.
我不才的弟弟并非“产物”
And even if you light it on fire, the world won't be singed at all.
你们烧过的地方 不会给这个世界带来一点焦痕
I won't help you.
我不会帮你们
I won't try to stop you either.
也不会妨碍你们
All I will do is pity you,
我只会为你们怜悯
and pray for you.
为你们祈祷
For your everlasting revenge.
祝你们悠久的复仇能如愿以偿
Leave this place, please.
所以能请你们退去吗
In the name of Agakura Majiri.
就看在我阿牙仓万姬理的面子上
What was that just now?
刚才是怎么回事
You know these people, Maa?
他们是万姐的熟人吗
Yeah, you could call them friends.
是的 他们就像我的朋友一样
There's no use meddling with people dressed in that rain gear.
不必对那些穿着雨衣的人出手
No matter how many you stamp out,
因为就算我们想消灭他们
there's just no end to them.
也没办法将他们彻底消灭
Who are these guys?
这些家伙
It's like they don't even see us.
他们好像连看都不看我们一眼
They've got quite the grudge against Habaki.
好像对幅木有着深仇大恨一样
Not yet. This can't be the end.
不可以 我还不能死…
Mr. Iwa.
岩先生
These guys are moving strangely.
那些家伙的样子很奇怪
You want to know the secret of Fire-breathing Bug's tricks?
你想知道赴火之虫那些魔术的秘密吗
Yes.
没错
Since you don't want to show up,
既然你不想出面
then I want to hear what your remuneration is.
那我就听听你说的报酬是什么吧
I'll only give you a hint.
那么 我就给你一点提示
Fire-breathing Bug is one person, but not just one person.
赴火之虫是一个人但又并非一个人
They're as close as it gets to being someone with supernatural powers, or even a wizard,
他非常接近超能力者或魔法师
but they're simply the personification of the fruits of technology.
可以说他是有些脱离常识的 技术结晶的具象化
It can't be…?
这…难道…
Arase!
荒濑
Get the fire extinguisher!
你把灭火器拿来
Got it.
遵命
Hello.
喂
Why are you targeted by the Fire-breathing Bug?
你为什么会被赴火之虫盯上
Darn it.
可恶
Good grief.
真是的
Solitaire is enough.
变魔术的有一个雪天鸦就够了
You guys are like gamma knives.
你们呀 就像伽马刀一样呢
What does that mean?
什么意思
You're firing gamma rays in all directions.
你们从四面八方向外发射伽马射线
Just like a medical device that removes lesions.
就像切除病灶的医疗装置一样
You send your punishing fire
沿著名为线索的这条线
all along this line we call a clue, consuming any sinners we find there.
用你们那制裁的火焰 烧尽所有与这条线有交集的罪人
But if you misfire, it can cause a miscarriage of justice.
不过 你们要是射偏了 可就酿成冤案了哦
Sometimes what that nasty sir says comes in handy.
讨厌的老师所说的话 偶尔也会派上用场
So the Fire-breathing Bug is probably using lasers or some other method
赴火之虫他们 恐怕也是通过激光什么的
to burn the intersection…
把接触到的地方给…
No.
不
Is it possible to burn remote to here accurately enough to write this?
远距离操作还能正确地书写文字
That's impossible.
这不可能吧
Think outside the box.
换个思路吧
Nothing is impossible.
这世上没有不可能
We've taken on plenty of guys
我们至今为止的对手
who defy the impossible already.
都是些超越了不可能的家伙
Geez.
真是的
It's about time for the real monsters to come out!
真正的怪物差不多也该出来了吧
Hey!
喂
Let's get out of here first.
我们先从这里出去吧
Maybe that bastard Higuro will come back with reinforcements.
冰黑那个混蛋说不定会带救兵回来
What about this guy?
这个人怎么办呢
The guys who were singing
唱歌的人…
are all gone?
不见了吗
Who on earth was…
他们究竟是…
Someone's coming.
有人来了
Might be an enemy.
说不定是敌人
Impressive.
真是厉害
He caught me.
居然被他给发现了
I thought no one would notice us.
我还以为没有人能察觉到我们
Hmm, but
嗯 不过
he didn't notice Maa.
他好像没能察觉到万姐
Long time no see.
好久不见
My sweet little kid-sassin.
非常可爱的 少年暗杀者
Your current prosthetic is
你现在的义肢
very well-made.
做得还真是精致呢
But, didn't I tell you?
可是 我不是说过了吗
Sweet little boy.
可爱的少年
If you become my little brother,
只要你做我的弟弟
I'll give you back your arms and legs anytime.
我随时都可以把你的四肢还给你
So,
看来…
you really did come back to Japan.
你真的回日本了啊
It was supposed to be an easy job.
那本该是一个简单的任务
They were small-timers,
目标只是一个小人物
the perfect targets for my first job.
对于第一次接任务的我来说 这个目标是再适合不过了
But those small fries
然而…这个小人物
were also being targeted by another group.
却被其他人给盯上了
Killing anyone in the building.
把大楼里的家伙都杀掉
That's the task I was given.
这就是我收到的任务
I didn't hesitate.
我没有犹豫
My blade cut the girl's throat.
我的刀划过了那个女人的脖子
She should be dead.
她应该已经死了才对
Such a strong killing intent.
好棒的杀意啊
And you're cute.
而且你还很可爱
The latest model of killing machine raised by the Lei family.
不愧是雷家培养的最新型杀人机器
I've made up my mind.
我决定了我决定了
Won't you let the Agakuras adopt you?
你 要不要来当阿牙仓的养子呢
I didn't understand what she meant.
我不懂她在说什么
But what I truly didn't understand was what came after.
但真正让我摸不着头绪的 是接下来发生的事
The Heilei is a terribly cruel place, isn't it?
黑雷可是个非常可怕的地方哦
You must have an intimate understanding of that.
你应该已经亲身体会到了吧
When I came to,
等我意识到的时候
my limbs were gone.
我的四肢已经不见了
Oddly enough, there wasn't that much blood.
不可思议的是 我觉得我并没有流那么多的血
Don't worry.
没事的
I did it in such a way that you wouldn't die.
我特意让你活了下来
But how will the Heilei deal with you?
可是黑雷会怎么处置你呢
Call my name when you need help.
你想求助的话就呼唤我的名字吧
I'll come running to your side.
我很快就会赶来的
And when that happens, I'll give you back your limbs.
到时我会把你的四肢还给你
I'll consider you as my new family member,
我会把你当作我的新家人
and take good care of you.
好好疼爱你的
Big sis is so fickle.
姐姐你还真是见异思迁呢
Um.
嗯
But it's her first time cutting off someone else's limbs.
不过她还是第一次砍掉了别人的四肢
Maa must really like him.
万姐对他相当中意呢
Let's see each other again, okay?
我们以后再见吧
My cute little kid-sassin.
可爱的暗杀者
My name is…
我的名字是⋯
Agakura Majiri.
阿牙仓万姬理
So
所以
what'll it be?
你决定怎么做呢
You just called my name, didn't you?
你刚刚叫了我的名字 对吧
Do you want my help?
你是在寻求我的帮助吗
Help?
帮助
If you become my family member,
如果你成为我的家人
I'll slaughter the Heilei who've been so terrible to you.
我可以把你讨厌的那些黑雷的人 通通都杀掉哦
It's true
我确实
I despise the Heilei.
讨厌黑雷
However,
可是
I don't hate the blood I've inherited from them.
我不讨厌我身上流淌的血
Or rather, the technology itself, I don't hate that much.
准确来说 我不讨厌我这身本领
And,
而且
I don't belong
我的归宿
with either the Lei family or the Agakuras.
既不是雷家也不是阿牙仓
My blood
我身上流淌的血
is lightning that will protect the Shinoyama!
是守护四乃山家的“雷”
I miscalculated.
我失算了
I didn't expect Shinoyama to save you before I had the chance.
没想到四乃山家抢先我一步拯救了你
What the heck, Majiri?
搞什么啊 万姬理姐姐
You've been crushing on him for close to 10 years and now you've been dumped.
你都单恋人家快要十年了 却还是被甩了
Oh? So you're alive, Momo.
哎呀 你还活着啊小百
Big sis is so happy to see that.
姐姐我好高兴呀
But I don't appreciate you laughing at your sister's broken heart.
可你竟然敢嘲笑我失恋了 这让我很难过呢
I'll punish you later.
我之后再惩罚你
If you punish me now, I could die, you know.
你现在要是惩罚我 我可是会死的哦
Momo ended up in such a pitiful defeat, huh?
小百竟然会输得这么惨
You've made quite great progress.
你进步挺大的嘛
My little kid-sassin.
可爱的暗杀者
No, sis.
不 姐姐
The one who did this to me was the girl right above you.
我是被姐姐你头上的人给打败的哦
Be careful, sis.
你要小心哦 姐姐
That girl might be a pupil of Solitaire.
那家伙八成是雪天鸦的徒弟
She's got all sort of tricks up her sleeve.
她可是会变魔术的哦
Momoya is just a small figure who ranks seventh from the bottom in Agakura.
百矢不过是阿牙仓里 倒数第七的小人物
Isn't that just the middle level?
那不就是正中间的水平吗
Thanks.
谢谢
Very kind of you.
你真善良
What's your name?
你叫什么名字
Misaki, Misaki Sakimiya.
我叫美咲 崎宫美咲
Pleased to meet you.
请多指教
Agakura Misaki.
阿牙仓美咲
Sounds not bad.
听起来不错呢
Huh?
什么
Any chance you might take on the Agakura name?
小姑娘 你愿意继承阿牙仓的姓吗
SAKIYAMA AGAKURA MISAKI Maybe as a middle name?
(崎宫・阿牙仓・美咲) 如果是中间名的话可以哦
No.
不
AGAKURA SAKIMIYA MISAKI You should make the Sakimiya part your middle name.
(阿牙仓・崎宫・美咲) 崎宫才应该作为中间名
What kind of stupid conversation is this?
这个脑残的对话是怎么回事
Sis really can't keep her focus on just one person.
姐姐你真是见异思迁呢
There's no choice.
没办法
If this continues, my very lovely brother will die.
再这样下去 我非常可爱的弟弟会死掉的
Kana.
夏南
Yes.
嗯
Dahlia.
塔莉亚
Give me a weapon.
给我武器
It's a draw today.
今天就当作平手吧
We'll get going.
我们先走一步了
Apologies for breaking your prosthetic arm.
弄坏了你的义肢 我感到很抱歉
If you're willing to come to my house,
如果你愿意到我家来
I'll make it up to you with your original arm.
我可以把你原来的手赔给你
See you later.
以后再见吧
Misaki.
美咲
Hey, are we just letting them go like this?
喂 就这样放他们走吗
I can't do anything.
我不行了
That attack earlier busted one of my legs.
我的一只脚刚刚也被弄坏了
Hmm, I don't think I can do anything either.
嗯 我也不行了
I have been stabbed by Polka before.
波尔卡之前不是刺穿过我吗
That girl
那个人
compared to Polka then might be even stronger.
恐怕比那时的波尔卡还要强
I've lost my position.
我的地位已经没了
Get up, inspector.
站起来啊 警视正大人
Darn it.
可恶
How could the bug know my face?
我竟然会在这种地方 被虫子给知道了长相
Powder?
药粉
Did you just swallow that? Hey!
你刚才吃下去了吗 喂
So,
那么
it doesn't matter if I act up.
就算我大闹一场也没关系了吧
Mr. Iwa!
岩先生
Are you alright?
您没事吧
Thanks for saving me.
谢谢 你救了我一命
That strength just now…
刚才那股力量是怎么回事
I can't die here.
我绝对不能在这种地方死去
Was it the effect of some kind of drug?
是某种药物的作用吗
You've finally shown your true colors.
你终于露出马脚了
Hey! You're basically advertising that your soul's pitch-black!
你已经黑得不能再黑了呢
Nothing is simply black or white.
哪有什么白色和黑色
In this world, there is no color.
毕竟这个世界 根本就还没有什么颜色
Yes.
没错
Before long, he will bore a hole.
那个人再过不久 就会给这个世界穿个洞的
What are you talking about?
你在说什么
He must be crazy.
他疯了吧
So…
接下来…
Who should we take out first?
我们该先处理哪一边呢
I hope Takumi and the others are okay.
匠他们没事吧
Looks like there'll be a thunder.
好像要打雷了
Thunder.
雷…
Hmm.
嗯
I though the presence of elf was weak in this world,
虽然这边的世界几乎没有精灵的气息
the density of lightning elf isn't all that different from the world I came from.
但雷精灵的密度 却跟我所存在过的世界差不多
Thunder elf.
雷精灵
Can't you make a pact with them to use their magic?
跟他们签订契约后 就可以使用魔法了吗
I am not an elf sorcerer.
我并不是精灵术士
It'd be suicide for anyone other than an expert
除非是专门的术士
in the discipline to directly take in magic from thunder elf.
不然吸收雷精灵的魔力 就跟自杀没什么两样
However, a few geniuses can do this.
不过也有少数的天才能做到这一点
I am quite satisfied.
我很满意
The elves of this country are quite tasty.
这个国家的精灵非常美味呢
What? I can't hear you, boss!
啥 我完全听不清楚 你在说什么啊 老大
My ears are ringing from all the thunder.
雷声都快把我的耳朵震聋了
Show a little consideration.
你也替我们想想啊
Oh, sorry.
是吗 抱歉抱歉
This world is really interesting.
这边的世界真的很有趣呢
But it seems there are also annoying bugs here.
不过这里似乎也有讨厌的虫子
Everyone seems to be taking action of some kind or another.
他们都在蠢蠢欲动呢
Especially those hands in that building.
特别是大楼上的那些手
Who'd have thought they'd appear in such a remote island country like this?
没想到遥远的岛国居然还有这般景象
Is it something forced over from the other side of the hole?
是从对面打开的洞穴吗
Or is it but a whim by the destructive Wyvern Ordom?
或者是破空龙奥尔多姆的任性所为呢
Are you sure you should be showing that mark on your back?
那个 你背上的符号不要紧吗
It's no need to hide it anymore, right?
已经没必要再藏起来了吧
After all, it was created by a trickster in this country.
毕竟这是这个国家里 一个变魔术的人给搞出来的
Ah!
啊
I'm getting so excited now!
我总觉得自己现在好雀跃呀
I'll have to track him down fast and give him a proper welcoming.
得赶快找到他并好好庆祝一下才行
After all, this is my first time hosting a hometown guest.
毕竟这是我第一次迎接同乡的客人呢
(Episode18: The Revenge)
(第18集 The Revenge-复仇-)